Cornelius Osgood Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
Cornelius Osgood Archives
1934-1973
ANTAR.000002
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
10
A portion of the archives of Cornelius Osgood, accumulated during his time at Yale.
Osgood, Cornelius, 1905-1985
Biographical Sketch
Cornelius Osgood (b. 1905, d. 1983) was Curator of Anthropology at the Yale Peabody Museum from 1934 to 1973. He brought significant collections to the Museum from his research expeditions to the Arctic, China and Korea. Osgood may be best known for his research among the Athapaskan speaking people of interior Alaska, much of it published through the Yale University Publications in Anthropology series, and was also active in Connecticut archaeology.
Education
- Ph.B. University of Chicago, 1927
- Ph.D. University of Chicago, 1930
Field work
- Northwest Territory, Canada (1928-1929, 1931, 1932, 1934, 1937)
- Yunnan, China, began 1938
- Yale Caribbean Anthropological Program, began in 1933
--Lake Valencia, Venezuela
--Chiriqui Province, Panama
Description of the Material
Miscellaneous archives accumulated during Cornelius Osgood's time at the Peabody Museum.
Connecticut; Alaska; Venezuela; Cuba; Panama; Field notebooks; Class notes; Manuscript materials; Correspondence; Diaries; Yale Peabody Museum; Yale University
- Teaching Materials, 1934-1973; Series I
- Research Materials, 1934-1973; Series II
  Scope and Contents
  1 box of folders from file cabinet at 175 Whitney- boxed during the move 2007- Some electronic files added from Alaska.
  - C. Osgood Diaries 1943-1973 from research expeditions., 035885
  - Photographs from Anvik, Alaska by C. Osgood. These are electronic copies only, of objects that are held by the Rasmusen Library in Fairbanks, Alaska. The Peabody Museum does not hold copyright. These photos are for internal use only., 036371
  - Field book from the 1928-1929 season recorded by C. Osgood. These are electronic copies only, of objects that are held by the Rasmusen Library in Fairbanks, Alaska. The Peabody Museum does not hold copyright. These materials are for internal use only., 036372
  - Collection of black and white photographs taken at an archeological site in Connecticut where C.B. Osgood did field work. These are electronic copies only, of objects that are held by the Rasmusen Library in Fairbanks, Alaska. The Peabody Museum does not hold copyright. These photos are for internal use only., 036373
  - Collection of black and white photographs taken at an archeological site in Cuba where C.B. Osgood did field work. These are electronic copies only, of objects that are held by the Rasmusen Library in Fairbanks, Alaska. The Peabody Museum does not hold copyright. These photos are for internal use only., 036374
  - Collection of black and white photographs taken at an archeological site in Florida where C.B. Osgood did field work. These are electronic copies only, of objects that are held by the Rasmusen Library in Fairbanks, Alaska. The Peabody Museum does not hold copyright. These photos are for internal use only., 036375
- Bibliographies, 1934-1973; Series III
- Manuscript Materials, 1934-1973; Series IV
- Correspondence, 1931-1973; Series V
  Osgood A-Z. 3.25 bankers boxes
- Miscellaneous, 1934-1973; Series VI